4th March, 2018

Director, Human Resource,

Dear Sir/Madam,

With this letter and the attached resume for your review, I am presently seeking a new challenge and would like to express my sincere interest in the Manager, Talent Management- Operations position you may have available. As an accomplished professional with 6 years of experience spearheading comprehensive operational and strategic Talent Management functions, I possess a wide range of knowledge and talents that will allow me to contribute toward the success of your company

My background lies in successfully directing developing and executing human resource strategy to align the overall business plan, Transformation leadership, organizational planning and performance through strategic processes and staff development. Throughout my career, I have managed recruitment procedures, Occupation Health & Safety standard, change management, succession planning, employee training initiatives, staff coaching and employee morale-boosting practices. Additionally, with a proven record in developing and implementing Talent/ Human Resource best practices, including talent acquisition, staffing, employment processing, compensation and benefits administration, training and development, employee and industrial relation along with a flair for creating work environments that attract and hold top-notch talent positions me to make a significant contribution to your organization.

The following achievements demonstrate my qualification for this position:

- Interviewing, hiring, and training top-performing teams while ensuring comprehensive adherence to organizational regulations and guidelines.
- Developing and implementing company-wide policies and procedures to establish standardization and drive staff compliance.
- Directing talent acquisition, performance evaluations, and special project / event management to generate streamlined, efficient operations and achieve corporate objectives..
- Developed and implemented New Employee Orientation to ensure employee inclusion in the department and understanding of company culture; resulted in faster assimilation of new employees
- Improved staff performance through the implementation of a full range of training and development programs.

My proven dedication to optimizing organizational success through my keen knowledge of Talent Management operations and strategies will contribute immensely to the success of the organisation. Thank you for your consideration and I look forward to speaking with you soon.

Yours sincerely,

DHANIRAM RAMNATH MBA, BA (Hons)

25B Lalbeharry Trace, Extension 1, Debe. Trinidad, WI

Tel: 647-0187, 482-4326, 331-3980 E- Mail: dramnath25@gmail.com

DHANIRAM RAMNATH

25B Lalbeharry Trace, Extension 1, Debe, Trinidad, WI. Tel: 1-(868)-647-0187, 1-(868)-482-4326, 1-(868)-331-3980 Email: dramnath25@gmail.com

Qualification Profile

Seasoned, employee- oriented and performance-focused professional with extensive experience and expertise in all areas of Talent Management, Business Strategy and the recruitment process; compliment with a well horned staff leadership and training capabilities in motivating employees to achieve and exceed organisation goals. Expert at evaluating employee performance, executing succession programs and cultivating strong employee relations

Core Professional Strengths

Strategic Talent Management and HR best practices

Training and Development

Talent Acquisition and Planning

Staff Coaching & Mentoring

Organisation

Development

Effectiveness

Workforce

Planning

Bevelopment

Workforce

Planning

Bevelopment

HR Policy, Process & Systems Design

Succession Planning

Employee Retention Initiatives & Engagement

Strategic HR Planning

Milestone Achievements

- Built Human Resource Department from the ground up, introduce several HR practices and procedure; first ever employee handbook aligned with company's best practise.
- Brought significant improvement to employee relations and workflow efficiency by providing strategic direction to all levels of employees in relation to performance, job duties and protocols and procedures.
- Align HR practices with business strategy that aims to attract, develop and retain talented employees at each level of the organization.
- Successfully lowered the turnover rate from 10% to 3% by implementing stronger guidelines for interviewing and screening potential candidates.
- Managed succession planning initiative resulting in reduction of hiring expenses by approximately 20%.
- Counseled managers and employees on individual HR issues including performance management, organizational and leadership development, compensation and employee relations.
- Improved staff performance through the implementation of a full range of training and development programs.
- Align succession planning needs to corporate goals and the organization's strategic vision
- Initiated performance-driven management processes for all levels of staff.

Professional Experience

Parliament of Trinidad and Tobago – 1st September, 2016- 27th December, 2017

Welfare Officer - Administering community welfare services

- the undertaking of the full management and administration of the office including staff supervision, performance reviews, procurement of materials, clients relations and all other related matter.

College of Science Technology and Applied Arts of Trinidad and Tobago- Sutton Street, San Fernando – (4th December, 2015- 5th August, 2016)

Human Resource Administrator

- Assisted in developing human resource plans and strategic Talent Management policies and procedures. Prepared various reports and related documents (e.g. agenda items, conference schedules, etc.) for the purpose of providing documentation and information to other.
- Assisted in the coordination of departmental events including orientation and registration.

Ministry of the Attorney General, The Chief State Solicitor Department- Cabildo Chambers, 23-27 St. Vincent Street, Port-of-Spain – (5th November 2012- 30th October, 2015)

Paralegal/ Human Resource Administrator

- Participated in the Ministry/ Department's strategic planning and change management process.
- Provided assistance in the performance management process in areas such as developing position descriptions and performance standards and ensuring timelines are met.
- Assisted in the monitoring and reviewing of government regulations to ensure that the Ministry and its agencies are aware of new requirements.

College of Science Technology and Applied Arts of Trinidad and Tobago- Sutton Street, San Fernando – 4th **July, 2011- 31st October 2012**

Administrative Assistant

- Assisted students with questions about classes, registration, permissions, etc. using established guidelines (information in course catalogs, departmental and college documents, and established policies and procedures).

Messrs Girwar and Deonarine Attorneys at Law - Harris Court, Nos. 17- 19 Court Street, San Fernando. **4th November 2010 –June 2011**

Legal Assistant

 Managed the daily running of First Citizens Bank (FCB) and The Trinidad & Tobago Mortgage Finance Company (TTMF) Mortgage Action (Judgment & Possession) Portfolio.

21st century Reinsurance & Insurance Brokers Limited - #65 Independence Ave., San Fernando 11th January 2010 – 25th June, 2010 (Temp

Human Resource Administrator/ Claims Assistant

- Administered all Human Resource Matters within the organization i.e. Coordinate and maintain records for staffing e.g. Sick leave, vacation, casual, bereavement; Prepared employment contract, Memos,

- Job letters, conducted interviews of staff regarding their concerns, grievances and needs at all levels and persons seeking employment.
- Drafted Employment Contracts and reviewed of all Contractual Agreements made by the organization.

Messrs. R. Rampersad & Co. – Attorneys at Law - 7a Harris Promenade, San Fernando July 2004 to January 2010-

Legal Assistant

Organized exhibits, files and all other supporting documents, coordinate trial set-up and logistics, assist attorneys in the courtroom by taking notes, handling exhibits, and marking documents referred to by counsel, assist in the preparation of witness testimony and serve as liaison between trial attorneys and in-house staff. Other Responsibilities- the undertaking of the full management and administration of the firm's office including staff supervision, performance reviews, procurement of materials, clients relations and all other related matters.

Education

- Master of Business Administration (MBA) with specialization in Strategic Human Resource
 Management and Talent Management, Merit Anglia Ruskin University U.K- (Awarded in April, 2016)
- Bachelor of Arts with Honours (HONS) Human Resource Management, Anglia Ruskin University U.K. (via School of Accounting and Management) (Awarded in October, 2011) (2007-2011)
- Certifications
 - Occupational Safety Health Authority Certificate of Training |
 Occupational Safety & Health Standards for the General Industry (Technical 30 Hour Program)

Technical Proficiency

HRIS, Oracle PeopleSoft, E learning System platforms, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Touch Typing, Internet research, Microsoft Project Research Skills, Information Technology

REFERENCES

Provided upon request